## Irina Joshi(she/her)

joshi.irina@gmail.com

4167166895

♠ Ontario, Canada

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY (https://www.linkedin.com/in/irina-joshi/)

A team player and a highly motivated software engineer willing to undertake challenging tasks. Varied software projects have honed my development & and analytical skills and have prepared me to work effectively on any challenging project.

- \* Well-versed in Software design and development; worked in domains like litigation and audit recovery, developing document management systems, healthcare, email visualization tools, Dashboards, and other reports.
- \* Specialization in Windows (Desktop) application development.
- \* Extensive experience in Enterprise Applications Development and Testing utilizing objectoriented programming concepts and MSFT tools/platforms.
- \* Strong Command of RDBMS such as MSSQL.
- \* Capable of working on multiple projects simultaneously.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE** &

### **Senior .NET Software Engineer**

Jul 2018 - Dec 2023

FlexTecs (<a href="https://flextecs.com/">https://flextecs.com/</a>) [ Domain: Audit Recovery]

- \* End-to-end test-driven development of custom software, APIs, and DLLs for the company's inhouse Audit Recovery Software ecosystem using mainly Microsoft .NET tools and platforms.
- \* Design, develop and document the software based on customers' requirements.
- \* Communicate with business clients, business executives, and other stakeholders to gather and analyze requirements and update them with development.
- \* Collaborate with CTO, operational managers, and solution architects, data team to plan, evaluate, and design new requirements and change requests.
- \* Participate in weekly team meetings with office executives to update the development status and discuss product roadmaps.
- \* Participate in weekly technical meetings with key members (offshore), including CTO, Operation Managers, product owners, and other engineering managers.
- \* Oversight and guide junior development and QA/QC team members' work as required.
- \* Quick prototyping and development of POCs.
- \* Responsible for maintaining the codebase and software release.
- Review product backlog, assigning tasks to team members.

#### **Senior Software Developer**

Mar 2010 - Jun 2018

NepaSoft Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (https://nepasoft.com/) [ Domain: Litigation and e-discovery]

\* Write, modify, integrate, and test code for the company's bespoke software and APIs

- developed for the Litigation domain using mainly Microsoft .NET tools and platforms.
- Design, develop and document the software based on customers' requirements.
- \* Worked in different visualization JavaScript libraries, AngularJS, elastic search, Apache Lucene, Alfresco open source for BPM, etc., for different research projects.
- \* Communicate with business clients, business executives, and other stakeholders to gather and analyze requirements and update them with development.
- \* Collaborate with team lead, solution architects, and data team to plan, evaluate, and design new requirements and change requests.
- \* Participate weekly team meetings with office executives to update the development status and discuss product roadmaps.
- \* Oversight and guide junior development and QA/QC team members' work as required.
- \* Quick prototyping and development of POCs.
- \* Responsible for maintaining the codebase and software release.
- \* Research new tools and technologies to apply to the company's products.

#### Senior Software Developer and QA/QC

Oct 2006 - Mar 2010

Data Analysis and Software Solutions (DASS)

- \* Worked closely with analysts, designers, and team leads.
- Presented ideas for system improvements.
- \* Produced detailed specifications and developed programs as per specs.
- \* Implemented new features and enhancements to the existing product as per the requirements.
- Conducted training sessions for the software users and created product documents, user manuals, etc.
- \* Developed and managed different release cycles (Scrum Sprints Management, Version Control System Management)
- Designed/developed analysis reports.
- \* Participated in R&D of new technologies for enhancing product performance and user experience.
- \* Performed different Tests (Unit testing, combination testing, system testing).

#### **EDUCATION**

| Post-Graduate in Project Management (PMPD) Cambrian College • Greater Sudbury, Ontario                | Mar 2023 - Oct 2023 |
|---|---------------------|
| Executive Master's in Business Administration White House International College • Kathmandu, Nepal    | 2009 - 2011         |
| Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering Nepal Engineering College • Changunarayan, Bhaktapur, Nepal | 2001 - 2005         |

**DOB** 28<sup>th</sup> December

#### REFERENCE

John Kidd (Chief Technology Officer at FlexTecs US)

Email: john.kidd@flextecs.com

## SKILLS 🛠

- \* Programming Languages: C#.Net, ASP.Net, C, C++, Java, JavaScript
- \* Markup/Data Exchange Languages: HTML, XML, JSON
- \* Architectural Pattern: Client-Server, n-tier, MVC, MVVM, REST API
- \* S/W Development Practices: SOLID Principles, Design patterns
- \* Testing Frameworks: CUnit, CGreen, NUnit, CodedUI, Selenium
- \* Databases: MSSQL, MS Access, MySQL
- \* JavaScript Frameworks and Library: jQuery, AngularJS, D3.js, eChart
- \* Web and Application Servers: Apache Web Server, IIS
- \* Version Control Systems: SVN, SourceForge, Microsoft Team Foundation Server (TFS)
- \* SCRUM Tools/Issue Trackers: Bugzilla, Redmine, Mantis
- \* Build Tools: Ant, Maven
- \* Integrated Development Environments (IDEs): Eclipse, Visual Studio (2005, 2008, 2010,2013, 2017)
- \* OS Platforms: Windows, Linux (RedHat Enterprises Linux, Fedora Linux, Ubuntu)
- \* Application and design software: MS Office Package, Photoshop
- \* Project Management: MS-Project
- Others: Entity Framework, Microsoft Interop, OpenXML, bootstrap, Message Queue
- \* Current Learning: PowerBI, Reactjs, Microservice architectures

#### **AWARDS**

# CAMBRIAN COLLEGE INTERNATIONAL EXCELLENCE BURSAR (PMPD 1st Semester)-2023 July

Cambrian College of Applied Arts and Technology

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

## Sr. Software Developer

https://48in48.org/

Jan 2022 - Dec 2022

Voluntary work to develop websites for social causes under the 48in48 program initiative.